Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
one of the first topics that Mike will share with you in a little bit is a deep
Mike将在稍后与你分享的第一个主题是：深
入了解Transformer网络的工作原理。
dive into how transformer networks actually work.
Yeah, so look, it's a complicated topic, right?
是的，这是一个复杂的话题，对吗？
In 2017, the paper came out, Tension is all You Need, and
2017年发表的论文《Attension is all You Need》详细阐述了在
Transformer架构中会发生的一系列相当复杂的数据处理过程。
inside the transformer architecture.
So we take a little bit of a high level view, but we do go down into some depths.
我们会从高层次的角度进行讨论，但也会深入探究一些内容。
We talk about things like self-attention and
我们会讨论自注意力和多头自注意力机制等内容。
the multi-headed self-attention mechanism.
So we can see why it is that these models actually work,
这样我们就能理解这些模型为什么有效，它们是如何理解语言的。
how it is that they actually gain an understanding of language.
And it's amazing how long the transformer architecture has been around
Transformer已经存在了很长时间，令人惊奇
的是，它仍然是许多模型的最先进技术。
and it's still state of the art for many models.
I remember after I saw the transformer paper when it first came out, I thought,
我记得当我第一次看到Transformer论
文时，我觉得，是的，我懂这个等式。
yep, I get this equation.
But what's it actually doing?
但它实际上是做什么的？
And it's always seemed a little bit magical.
这一直似乎有点神奇。
It took me a long time playing with it to finally go, okay, this is why it works.
我花了很长时间去研究它，最后终于明白，这就是它有效的原因。
some of these terms you may have heard before, like multi-headed attention.
What is that and why does it make sense?
那是什么，它的意义是什么？
And why did the transformer architecture really take off?
为什么Transformer架构真正流行起来？
I think attention had been around for a long time, but actually thought it was,
我认为注意力机制（Attention）已经存在了很长时间，但我认为真
正让它流行起来的是，它允许注意力以大规模并行的方式工作。
attention to work in a massively parallel way.
I think these nuances around transformers are not well-understood by many, so
我认为很多人并不了解关于Transformer的这些细
微之处，所以我期待你们能深入研究这个问题。
looking forward to when you deep dive into that.
Absolutely, I mean, the scale is part of it and
绝对的，我想说的是，规模是一部分，它能够处理所有的数据。
how it's able to take in all that data.
I just want to say as well, though, that we're not going to go into this at such
我只是想说，我们不会在这个问题上深入到让人头疼的程度。
a level which is going to make people's heads explode.
If they want to do that, then they can go ahead and read that paper too.
如果他们想这样做，他们可以去阅读那篇论文。
What we're going to do is we're going to look at the really important
我们要做的是，我们要看看那个Transformer架构的真正重要的部分，
parts of that transformer architecture that gives you the intuition you need so
让你得到你需要的知识，这样你就可以实际地利用这些模型。
that you can actually make practical use out of these models.
One thing I've been surprised and delighted by is how transformers,
一件让我感到惊讶和高兴的事情是，虽然这个课程主要关注文本，
even though this course focuses on text, it's been really interesting to see
how that basic transformer architecture is creating a foundation for
但看到基础的Transformer架构如何为视觉
Transformer创建基础实在是非常有趣。
vision transformers as well.
So even though in this course you learn mostly about large language models,
所以，虽然在这门课程中你主要学习的
是大语言模型、关于文本的模型，
models about text, I think understanding transformers is also helping people
我认为理解Transformer也有助于人们理解这种非
常激动人心的视觉Transformer以及其他形式。
understand this really exciting vision transformer and other modalities as well.
a lot of machine learning.
Absolutely.
绝对的。
And then beyond transformers, there's a second major topic that looking forward
然后，除了Transformer，还有第二个主要的话题，
to having this first week cover, which is the Generative AI project Lifecycle.
期待在这第一周覆盖，那就是生成式AI项目生命周期。
I know a lot of people are thinking, boy, does all this LM stuff, what I do of it?
我知道很多人在想，哇，所有这些LLM的项目，我该怎么去构建呢？
And the Generative AI project Lifecycle, which will talk about in a little bit,
生成式AI项目生命周期，我们稍后会谈到，它可以
帮助你规划如何构建你自己的生成式AI项目。
helps you plan out how to think about building your own Generative AI project.
That's right, and
没错，生成式AI项目生命周期会引导你了解在开发
生成式AI应用时需要做出的各个阶段和决定。
So one of the first things you have to decide is whether you're taking
所以你首先需要决定的是，是选择一个现成的基
础模型，还是实际上要预训练你自己的模型，
then as a follow up, whether you want to fine tune and
然后作为后续，你是否希望微调和定制该模型以适应你的特定数据。
customize that model maybe for your specific data.
Yeah, in fact, there's so many large language model options out there,
是的，事实上，现在有很多大语言模型可供选择，
which of these models do I want to use?
And so having a way to evaluate it and then also choose the right model sizing.
因此，有一个评估并选择正确模型大小的方式是非常重要的。
I know in your other work, you've talked about when do you need a giant model, 100
我知道在你的其他工作中，你谈到过何时需要一
个巨大的模型，比如1000亿甚至更大的模型，
billion or even much bigger versus when can a 1 to 30 billion parameter model or
相对的，何时一个1到30亿参数的模型或者小于10
亿参数的模型对于特定的应用来说就足够好？
Exactly, so there might be use cases where you really need the model to be very
确实，可能有一些使用场景，你真的需要模型非常全面，
comprehensive and able to generalize to a lot of different tasks.
能够适应很多不同的任务。
And there might be use cases where you're just optimizing for
也可能有一些使用场景，你只是为了单一的使用场景进行优化，对吧？
a single-use case, right?
And you can potentially work with a smaller model and achieving similar or
你可能只需要使用一个小一些的模型
就能获得相似甚至非常好的结果。
even very good results.
Yeah, I think that might be one of the really surprising things for
是的，我认为这可能是一些人会感到非常惊讶的事情，
some people to learn is that you can actually use quite small models and
那就是你实际上可以使用相当小的模
型，仍然能够从中获取很多的能力。
Yeah, I think when you want your large language model to have a lot of general
是的，我认为当你希望你的大语言模型具有很多关于世界的通用知识，
knowledge about the world, when you wanted to know stuff about history and
当你希望它知道关于历史和哲学的东西，知道
大小，知道如何编写Python代码等等时。
philosophy and the sizes and how to write Python code and so on and so on.
But for a single task like summarizing dialogue or
但是对于像对话总结或者作为一家公司的客户
服务代理这样的单一任务，对于这样的应用，
acting as a customer service agent for one company, for applications like that,
sometimes you can use hundreds of billions of parameters models.
有时候你可以使用上百亿参数的模型。
So lots of really exciting material to get into this week.
所以本周有很多真正令人兴奋的材料要深入研究。
With that, let's go on to the next video when Mike will kick things off with
那么，让我们进入下一个视频，Mike将开始深
入探讨大语言模型的许多不同使用案例。
a deep dive into many different use cases of large language models.